不 我们还没到
No, we are not there yet
不过应该就在这山崖后面 大黄蜂
but it should be just past this ridge, Bumbobee.
我不明白 读数爆表了
I don’t get it. These readings are off the metre.
我跟你说过了 医生 我们没事！
I told you, doc, we are fine.
惟一确认你没事的方法 隔板
The only way to be certain you are fine, Bulkhead
是耐心接受标准除霜处理
is to enduring standard defrosting procedure.
你清楚长期暴露在低温下
You know prolonged exposure to sub-zero conditions
会造成永久性系统损伤
can cause permanent system damage.
救护车 我们在北极发现的东西你调查清楚了吗？
Ratchet, have you learned anything more about our Arctic find.
还没有
Not yet.
舱门被冻住了 暂时打不开
The pod can’t be opened while it’s frozen solid.
阿尔茜和我去调查
Arcee and I will search for any clue
这个从北极来的东西究竟源自何方
which might explain the origin of our arctic find.
感应器一响就马上回来
Only until your sensors sound.
记住 如果你的核心温度降至蓝色区域
Remember, once your core temperature drops into the blue zone
很可能发生系统瘫痪 后果很严重
system failures are likely. They are eminent.
想我们了吗 机器医生？
Missed us doc bot?
他们不是应该在上学吗？
Uh, shouldn’t they be in school?
在星期六？我们整个周末都有空…来陪你
On Saturday? We have the whole weekend off, to spend with you.
我本来不想拼车的
I wasn’t expecting a car pool.
什么情况 阿尔茜？
What gives, Arcee?
很诱人 杰克
Tap team, Jack.
轮到我执行探索任务
It’s my turn for exploration duty.
噢 真不巧
Oh, too bad.
今天是个兜风的好日子
It’s a beautiful day for a ride.
把我扔在家 你可能会有负罪感啊
Would hate for you to feel guilty for leaving me indoors.
北极探索任务
Arctic exploration duty.
那还是家里暖和
Indoor’s where is warm.
北极？
The Arctic?
我一直想去看雪呢
I’ve always wanted to see snow.
我很乐意邀你同行 拉斐尔
I would invite you to join, Raphael.
但那里的条件过于恶劣
But the conditions are much too extreme.
哪怕对我们汽车人来说
Even for we Autobots.
我…理解
I... understand.
不过 我会给你带一个雪球回来
But I will bring you back a snow ball.
那太棒了！
That would be awesome!
传送完成
Transport complete.
我的火种源啊！
Oh, by the Allspark.
那么 你们说今天该干什么？
So, what do you guys think we should do today?
电子游戏时间 看谁是最后的赢家！
Video game turn! The last one standing wins!
隔板 大黄蜂 赶快过来！
Bulkhead, Bumbobee! Here, now!
准备受死吧！
Prepare to be destroyed!
嗯 没错 我不太擅长这个 神子
Eh, yea, not really my thing, Miko.
噢 是怕输给女孩子吧？
Oh, scared of losing to a girl?
放马过来吧！
Uh, bring it!
绝不手软！
No mercy.
嘿 拉夫 想替我摆平神子吗？
Hey Raf, you want to take on Miko for me?
不 我有事要做
Nap, I have stuff to do.
老大不在 你也不能随便使唤我们啊！
You can't boss us around because the boss is out!
我需要人帮忙干活 环陆桥坏了！
I need some heavy lifting. The ground bridge is down.
擎天柱和阿尔茜出发顺利
Optimus and Arcee made it through just fine.
我担心的是怎么把他们接回来
It's bringing them back that concerns me.
现在把那些仪表搬开 要快！
Now remove those panels, chop, chop!
气温在零下并持续下降
Temperature sub-zero and dropping...
不行了…得返回…基地
Not a... get back... to base...
有人吗？
Hello?
你是哪儿来的？
Where did you come from?
汽车人从没提起过宠物
Haha. The Autobots never said anything about pets.
想玩接东西吗？
You wanna play fetch?
好孩子 去捡回来！
Uh, hehe good boy. Go get it.
不 别吃！
No, don’t eat that!
你会噎着的！
You’re gonna choke!
或许…不会？
...or not?
来吧 来吧 尝尝厉害…
Come on, come on. You want some...
大获全胜！
Ate your face!
怎…怎么回事？！
What the...
好极了 停电了！
Great, power fail.
啊 我们的游戏被中断了！
Eh, it wiped out our game!
你…怎么能
You, but, uh
我明明赢了！
I was winning!
认了吧
Bummer!
我们一定是遇到了什么问题
We definitely have a problem.
但到底是什么导致的这个…
But what could have caused this?
或是那个
Or that?
可能是主电网
Might be the main grid.
但愿不是配电站的问题
Hopefully it isn't a substation malfunctioning.
嘿 伙计们 瞧我找到了什么？
Hey guys, look what I found?
我们很忙！
We are busy! Ah!
嘿 嘿 你们怎么了？
Hey, hey, what's with you guys?
吸屑虫！吸屑虫！！！
Scraplet, scraplet!
吸屑虫是什么？
What's a scraplet?
塞博特恩有史以来最危险的害虫！
The most dangerous vermin ever to crawl upon the face of Cybertron.
就它？
A this?
你在开玩笑吗？
Are you kidding me?
你们是巨型机器人！
You are giant robots!
而这虫虫…小得很
Scrappy here is tiny.
你没见识过这个小东西的破坏力！
You have no idea the damage that tiny thing could do!
啊 他不会伤害任何东西
Eh, he wouldn't hurt any thing.
行了 放松 小杀手
Alright, easy there, killer.
哇噢 我没想到会是这样
Whoa, I did not see that coming.
对不起 大黄蜂！
I'm sorry, Bumbobee.
你会好起来吗？
Is it gonna be OK?
只是皮外伤
Only a mesh wound
他死不了
he'll live.
你现在相信我了吧？
Now do you believe me?
吸屑虫会肢解机器 然后吃掉所有金属部分
All scraplets do is dismantle machinery and eat anything metal
尤其是活的金属！
especially living metal.
那么 虫子已经被打扁了 应该没事了吧？
Well, bug squashed, game over, right?
不！
No.
吸屑虫绝不会独来独往
When it comes to Scraplets there is never just one.
恐怕我知道他们是怎么进来的了
And I fear I know how they got in here.
这是个笼子
It’s a trap
用来抓吸屑虫的！
a Scraplet trap.
嗯…空的吸屑虫笼子？
Eh, an empty Scraplet trap?
可能是远古时期发射到太空的
Most likely ejected into space eons ago.
最终掉到了北极 低温使他们一直休眠
Only to wind up in the Arctic when the temperature kept them in stasis.
直到我们把他们弄出来
Until we brought the thaw.
现在他们苏醒过来 并蓄势待发
Now they are wide awaken and ready to branch.
那…
So...
他们有多少？
how many are we talking about?
成百上千
Thousands.
电力故障和环陆桥的损坏
The power malfunctions and ground bridge damage
明确表明他们正在侵蚀这里
are sure signs that their infestation is well under way.
阿尔茜 你的情况怎么样？
Arcee, what's your status?
我的感应器响了
My sensors' are going off.
我们最好在冻僵之前打道回府
Guess we should call for pick up before things get chilling.
擎天柱呼叫基地
Optimus to base
核心温度读数降至蓝色区域
core temperature readings have reached the blue zone.
准备启动环陆桥
Prepare to activate Ground Bridge.
救护车呼叫擎天柱 你能听到吗？
Ratchet to Optimus, do you read me?
我们遇到了麻烦
We have a situation.
吸屑虫侵入了通讯系统！
Scraplets have got into the com-link system.
如果我们不立即清除这些生物
If we don't eradicate these creatures immediately
他们会将整个基地变成一团废渣！
they will reduce the entire base to a scrappy.
我说我们还是开溜 让他们占领好了！
I say we bug out of here and let them keep it.
我们不能转移
Evacuation is not an option.
如果我们不修复环陆桥
If we don't get the Ground Bridge back online stat
擎天柱和阿尔茜会被冻死
Optimus and Arcee will perish.
那 好吧…
The... Well...
隔板 你从不退缩的！
Bulkhead, you never run!
神子 你没见过一群虫子活吃机器人的情景
Miko, you haven't seen the swarm of this thing devour a bot.
我见过
I have.
他们从里到外把你拆开
They pick you apart from the inside out.
从小而多汁的部分开始
Going for the small, juicy bits first
每根导线 每条电路
fuse by fuse, circuit by circuit
吃个精光！
till there's nothing left.
我说的是精光！
And I mean nothing!
连视觉电路都不剩
Not even your optics.
你得让我们帮忙
You have to let us help.
我们不是金属做的
We are not made of metal.
没错 吸屑虫伤不了我们
Yea, the Scraplets can't hurt us.
通常 我觉得你们的血肉之躯是最不中用的
Typically, I find your fleshiness to be your least engaging quality
但在极端情况下 似乎是一种优势
but it would appear to provide an advantage under these extremes.
很好
Ok, good.
我们结伴行动 一个汽车人配一个人类
So we pair off. One bot, one human.
我来掩护你维修环陆桥
I'll watch your back while you repair the Ground Bridge.
那我们就去杀虫
And we go in a bug hunt.
擎天柱呼叫基地 听到了吗？
Optimus to base, do you read.
你觉得我们来个千里奔袭如何？
Are you sure a nice long drive wouldn’t help?
我听说这个时节的迈阿密气候宜人
I hear Miami is beautiful this time of year.
最近的温带地区离这里太远了 阿尔茜
The nearest temperate climate is too distant, Arcee.
去那里要消耗太多能量
Attempting to reach it would expend too much energy
会加快冰冻的速度
and hasten the freezing process.
要坚持到救护车找到我们
Until Ratchet sense for us
他一定会的
and he will.
眼下的明智之举是寻找避风港
Our best option will be to seek shelter
以保持体温
and insolate ourselves.
我能当一回你的保镖 多么酷啊！
I get to be your bodyguard for once, how cool is that?
拉斐尔在这儿发现了第一个 对吧？
Raphe found the first one here, right? Ahhhh!
你刚刚像小女孩一样尖叫了吗？
Did you just scream like a little girl?
没有！
No.
或许吧
Maybe.
我们以后再讨论这个好吗？
Can we talk about this later?
别紧张 隔板
Take it easy, Bulkhead.
集中精神就好 一切都会…
Just stay focused. Everything’s gonna be...
啊 我的天 离我远点！
Ah, my god, get out of me!
好吧 真希望我没看到这场面
OK, wish I hadn't seen that.
隔板 你没事！
Bulkhead, you are fine.
那只是一些电缆
It's just a bunch of cables.
嗯 对 电缆
Eh, ho, right. Cables. Hehe.
这些东西一直吃个不停吗？
Don't these things ever stop eating?
那边进展得怎么样了？
How's it going over there?
我修好了受损的导体
I've repaired the damaged conductors
重接了中央枢纽
and rerouted the central cond-roots;
可环陆桥还是无法恢复动力！
But Ground Bridge still won't receive power!
它们会飞？
They fly?
你从没说过他们会飞！
You never said they could fly!
救护车！
Ratchet!
用灭火器！
The fire-extinguisher!
救护车 准备急救包
Ratchet, get a patch kit.
我们的能量泄露得…哇哦！
We are leaking energon like... Wow!
吃这个吧！
Eat this! Ahhh!
阿尔茜 醒一醒！
Arcee, wake up.
我只是在闭目养神
Ugh. Just resting my eyes.
我们保持清醒越久
The longer we remain alert
就能存活越久
the longer we remain alive.
你有什么提议？
What do you suggest?
等等 不如玩个游戏？
Wait, how about a game?
我们来玩“猜猜基地里谁把事情搞砸了”
Let's play "Who screwed  things up back at base".
一个简单的故障就有可能导致我们现在的困境
Our predicament could be the result of a simple malfunction.
隔板惹的祸
Caused by Bulkhead.
想想看 通讯失灵 可能连动力都没了
Let's see. No com-link, maybe even no power.
那个大块头很可能绊倒在了某根线上
The big lug probably tripped over a cord.
他永远也学不会优雅
He's never been too graceful.
记得我们刚到地球的时候吗？
Remember when we first arrived on earth
隔板踩到了供电线路
and Bulkhead walked into those power lines?
谁能想象他手舞足蹈的样子？
Hmhm, who would know he can dance like that?
隔板对这个世界来说或许过大了
Bulkhead may be too large for this world
但他内在的力量与我们紧密相联
but his inner strength is with our bond.
不能单凭个头来评判一个人
One should not be measured by size along.
把他们全消灭了吗？
We get them all?
一部分
Partly.
这些只是侦察兵
These were just scouts.
那么…剩下的那些知道我们在这儿了？
So the... rest of them know we're in here?
如果我们成了他们的下一顿大餐
And if we allow ourselves to become their next meal
擎天柱和阿尔茜就再也回不来了
Optimus and Arcee will never make it home.
我们必须让环陆桥运作起来！
We must get the Ground Bridge operational.
然后用它把吸屑虫送到地球上的某处
Then we can use it to send Scraplets anywhere on earth.
直接送回北极怎么样？
Why not back to the Arctic?
我们已经知道他们怕冷
We already know that they don't do cold.
好主意！一举两得！
S-weet! One stop shopping!
根据吸屑虫的体质 零度以下的低温
Given the body mass of the Scraplets
应该能立即冻结他们
sub-zero condition should freeze them on contact.
快想 救护车 快想想！
So think, Ratchet, think!
如果环陆桥还不能工作
If the Ground Bridge is still down
只可能是能量输送管有裂口！
there must be a breach in the energon fuel line!
要不是我们也有裂口
If we weren't breaching
就可以派一个人去修好它
one of us can get back over there and fix it.
输送管在哪儿？
Where do we find it?
我们怎么修好它？
And how do we fix it?
别怕 我们没事
Remember, we are OK.
我们不是金属
We are not metal.
裂口在那儿！
There is the breach.
快！
Come on!
我们得快点！
We have to work fast!
如果我们能…
So if we get
撑到环陆桥开启时
when, we get the Ground Bridge open
是先把这些爬虫送出去
do we send the quippy crawlies out
还是先把自己人接回来？
or bring our bots in?
擎天柱和阿尔茜就像新鲜的鲜肉 如果他们先回来
Optimus and Arcee will be fresh meat.
吸屑虫是不会离开的
If we bring them in first, the Scraplets will have no reason to leave.
我们需要诱饵
We’ll need bait.
我们到哪儿去找诱饵？
Where are we gonna get bait?
吸屑虫早就把这儿当成自己家了！
The Scraplets are already helping themselves to everything in here!
他们准备开饭了！
They are getting ready to feed！
你知道最糟糕的是什么吗？
You know the worst part?
跟虎子们战斗了这么多年
After battling Cons all these years
被打躺过 射中过 炸飞过
getting smitten down, shot at, blown up
结果却是这么个死法？
this is how our lights go out?
阿尔茜 这或许不是我们意料中的结局
Arcee, This may not be the finish that we've planned
但如果真要在这里结束
but if this is indeed the end
如果我们要和火种源融为一体…
if we are to become one with the Allspark...
和你一起战斗很荣幸 擎天柱
It's been an honor serving with you, Optimus Prime.
救护车 全修好了！
Ratchet, all systems go!
发动它！
Fire it up!
环陆桥
Ground Bridge
启动…
activate...
诱饵 对吗？
Bait, eh?
准备好用主菜了吗？
Ready for the main course?
来吃我啊！
Come and get it! Ah!
卧倒 卧倒！
Down, down!
我邀请你们进来
I'd invite you in
不过家里一团糟
but the place is a mess.
汇报生化电路情况？
Report bio-circuitry status?
正在恢复中
Levels are rising.
很好
Excellent.
拉斐尔 看好大黄蜂的电脉冲监视器
Raphael, keep a close watch on Bumbobee's electro-pulse monitor.
神子 检查隔板的接口补丁
Miko, Check Bulkhead's interface patch.
情况稳定
It's steady.
一切正常！
Looking good.
或许你也该休息一下了 老朋友
Perhaps you should get yourself some rest, old friend.
你今天拯救了众多的生命
You saved quite a few lives today.
不…不全是我的功劳
It wasn't all my doing.
我们不过是幸运地赶上侵蚀发生在…
We're just fortunate that this infestation happened...
星期六
on a Saturday.
我们的人类朋友或许很渺小
Our human friends maybe small
但他们很强大
but they are strong.
又有吸屑虫？
A Scraplet?
蜘蛛！
Spider!
它爬我身上了吗？
Is it on me? Ah eh oh oh oh...
她刚刚像小女孩一样尖叫了吗？
Did she just scream like a little girl?